Kyle Rassweiler

Phone: 1-613-724-9141 Email: jobs@kylerassweiler.ca

Portfolio | Github | LinkedIn

Summary

I'm an **Engineering specialist** with experience in both software and hardware development with schooling focused on embedded development and robotics. I'm a self starter and quick to learn new technologies.

Skills

Software	Angular, Assembly(PIC), C++, CMake, Django, Git, HTML, JavaScript, Mongoose, Node, PHP, Python, React, Redux, SCSS, Typescript, VBA
Virtualisation	Docker, Proxmox, Qemu/KVM, XCP-NG
Systems	Arch, Debian, FreeBSD/OpenBSD, Windows
Databases	MongoDB, MySQL, Postgresql, SQLite
Hardware	Arduino, PIC, Raspberry Pi, Zigbee
PLC	Mitsubishi, Toyopuc, AB
Robots	Kawasaki, Nachi, Panasonic, Yaskawa
	Projects
Krello	A simple kanban web app made using Nextjs, React, tRPC, NextAuth, Prisma, and Typescript. The app is hosted on Vercel and Planetscale.
(Typescript, React, tRPC, Nextjs, NextAuth, Prisma, Vercel, Planetscale)	Site Source Demo
Random Quote Machine	A FreeCodeCamp project that generates random tweetable quotes using React.
(Javascript, SCSS, HTML, Node, React, Bootstrap)	<u>Source</u>
Markdown Preview	A FreeCodeCamp project that will preview markdown input into a seperate editor window.
(Javascript, SCSS, HTML, Node, React, Bootstrap)	<u>Source</u>
Krello	A simple kanban web app made using Nextjs, React, tRPC, NextAuth, Prisma, and Typescript. The app is hosted on Vercel and Planetscale.
(Typescript, React, tRPC, Nextjs, NextAuth, Prisma, Vercel, Planetscale)	Site Source Demo
React Pagination	A Hatchways assesment for React front-end work. The project required the addition of a pagination system for a sample blog site.
(Javascript, CSS, HTML, Node, React)	

Source

Certificates

	00. 12. 20. 100
Free Code Camp	JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures
Jul 2022	Certificate
July 2022	
Free Code Camp	Responsive Web Design
June 2022	<u>Certificate</u>
	Experience
Engineering Specialist	Commissioning, HMI design, PLC programming, Robotic Vision (Robeye , Omron, Keyence), 3D Factory Design (CAD), Robot programming, Project Management, Tools Programming (VBA, Powerbi, Electron).
2017 — Present	Hamagement, 100ts 110gramming (VDA, 10Werbi, Lieutron).
Work4ce (Toyota)	Highlights
	 Managed project implementation during non production time, ensuring no issues affect production and quality.
	• Implemented a new teach method that saved 75% of equipment recovery time, using a 4 point before-after comparison.
	 Setup production lines in 7 plants across North America for: Rav4, Camery, Hilander, Lexus NX, and Lexus RX. Production earne roughly 89 billion USD in 2022 across North America.
Robotics Technician	HMI design, PLC programming, Robot programming, SCADA programing.
2014 - 2017	Highlights
FIO Automotive	 Developed a proof of concept SCADA system using Angular, MongoDB and Node.js. The system allowed management to track downtime and target repeat issues during a 24/7 production period.
	 Setup networking for all production lines in order to implement my proof of concept and collect data to a MSSQL database.
Operational Technician	PLC programming, Robot programming.
2012 - 2014	
Abbott Point Of Care	
	Education
Electro-Mechanical Engineering Technician	Embedded development, plc programming, circuit and pcb design, motor controls, industrial robotics, microcontrollers.
Algonquin College	
Computer Animation	Traditional animation, 3d animation, riging, modelling, python scripting, layout.
Algenguin College	

Algonquin College